## Salun Marvin

## Senior Software Engineer & Product Manager

Currently living in Sete Lagoas/MG, Brazil
Phone +55 47 992922092
salunmarvin@gmail.com

Profile

I have been in Product Development, as a leader, engineer, and manager, for over 20 years, working on various projects with digital agencies, SaaS, and digital platform companies. I have acquired extensive knowledge of software development, innovation, leadership, people, project, and product management during my career.

Technical Skills

Scrum Agile Methodology and Product Management (from discovery to post-deployment) strong skills;

Software development in languages such as Python, Javascript, C#, PHP, Swift, and Groovy;

Software development using frameworks and libraries such as React, Redux, Mobx, Django, DRF, Symfony, Angular, CakePHP, NodeJS, ExpressJS, .NET, jQuery, and Bootstrap;

Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Git, RabbitMQ, REST APIs, relational databases, and non-relational databases; Fluent in English, Native Portuguese, and Intermediate Spanish.

Achievements

Working experience leading teams, managing 1-1s, feedback sessions, development plans, hirings;

Led product growth from scratch until deployment and analysis;

Led full-stack engineering teams, helping with architecture and technologies;

Led UX and UI designers throughout the product development;

Work Experience

## Head of Technology, FTW Co; Remote / Brazil • Mar 2023 - Present

- Built the architecture and code of a new version of the system from scratch, processing millions of media and files per month in a scalable way.
- · Hired and managed the product and engineering teams.
- Developed algorithms and features using Python, Flask, Django, Typescript, NextJS, Google Cloud Pub/Sub, Google Cloud Functions, PostgreSQL, Firestore.

Senior Full Stack Engineer / Product Manager, Bunny Studio; Remote / USA • Jun 2018 – Sep 2022 • 4 years 4 months

- Led several squads of different sizes (from 5 to 10 people), including full-stack engineers, tech leads, UX researchers, and UI designers;
- Improved the conversion of the home page and the search page from 3.68% to 5.83%;
- Increased the fulfillment rate, one of the main KPIs of the company, from 95% to 99%;
- · Helped the Tech Leads build the architecture and decide which technology to use in specific cases;
- Developed algorithms and features using PHP, React, AngularJS, Python, Node, and many other stacks;
- As an engineer, I've developed an algorithm that increased the number of auto-approval projects from 8% to 25%, which saved an average of 150k USD/year;

Senior Full-Stack Engineer, LOQUS Systems; Remote / Malta • Feb 2017 - May 2018 • 1 year 3 months.

- Worked as a full-stack engineer on a logistics application (tracking vehicles, depots, products, and stocks).
- · In the front end, the technology used was ReactJS and Mobx.
- In the backend, the technology used was NodeJS with ExpressJS and MongoDB as databases.
- Loqus was my first fully remote and international experience.

Founder, Comanda Smart ticketing app; Remote / Brazil • Jul 2015 – Jul 2022 • 7 years.

- · Comanda Smart was a ticketing app for restaurants and bars, mainly used for small companies in Brazil.
- · I've developed the product from scratch, including the design, architecture, demand test, and code.
- The first version of Comanda Smart was developed in Python and Django.
- · The second version of Comanda Smart was developed in NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, and React.
- The third and last version of Comanda Smart was developed in Python, Django, Postgres, and React.

Continues on the next page.

Engineering Manager & Scrum Master, Morphy; Blumenau / Brazil • Feb 2015 - Feb 2017 • 2 years.

- · Morphy is a digital agency that serves several clients in Brazil with customized systems.
- I managed a team of 5 to 8 engineers on several projects, including a videoconferencing app, mini-games, and a complete educational portal for English Schools.
- The team comprised front-end, back-end, iOS, Android, and DevOps engineers.
- I was responsible for tracking engineering performance and implementing SCRUM methodologies to execute continuous delivery and integration.
- · PHP, Symfony, Python, AngularJS, and MySQL were the most used technologies for these projects.

Software Engineer, Táticas E-learning; Belo Horizonte / Brazil • Aug 2008 - Sep 2009 • 1 year 1 month.

- · Taticas was the second biggest E-Learning company in Brazil.
- I built LMS (Learning Management System) platforms to host e-learning courses for companies like Vivo and MRV
- · The technologies used at Taticas were C#, .NET. SQLServer, TFS, PHP, Moodle, and Actionscript.

Software Engineer, Web-Aula E-learning; Belo Horizonte / Brazil • Feb 2008 – Aug 2008 • 6 months.

- · Webaula was the biggest E-Learning company in Brazil (later acquired by UOL).
- · At WebAula, I assembled e-learning courses for TOTVS and managed components using ActionScript.

Founder, Inventta Digital Agency; Belo Horizonte / Brazil • Jul 2004 - December 2018 • 14 years 6 months.

- Inventta was a digital agency in Brazil with hundreds of clients.
- We've developed systems and websites using technologies such as Python, Django, Flask, Tornado, PHP, Silex, Symfony, WordPress, ReactJS, AngularJS, MySQL, SQLServer, .NET, and C# among others.

Harvard Business School Online; Harvard, USA

Disruptive Strategy • 2021.

PM3; São Paulo, Brazil

Product Manager Certified • 2020.

SCRUMStudy; São Paulo, Brazil

SCRUM Product Owner Certified (SPOC) • 2020.

Product School; USA

Product Masterclass: How to build digital products certified • 2020.



Education